/*
    This code will:
        1]display questions one at a time
        2]display counter, count down
        3]evaluate question responses
            a.keep track of correct:incorrect responses
            b.subract time from counter for incorrect answers
        4]at end of quiz, get user initials
        5]display high scores

*/

/*

    step 01 (X):create array of question objects
        questions will have properties:
            -question
            -aswers[a,b,c,d]
            -correct answer = anwers[i]
    step 02 (X):create a function that renders questions to the page one at a time
    step 03 ():create a function that renders the high score list
    step 04 ():create a function that adds to the high scores
    step 05 ():create event listeners for user to select answer
    step 06 ():create event listeners for user input of initials/delet high schores
    step 07 ():create event listener to retake quiz/reset page
    step 08 ():create timer for quiz
    step 09 ():create function that evaluates user input

*/
//variables that will hold the questions and answers
var quizQuestion = document.querySelector(".question");
var multipleChoiceList = document.querySelector("#mulitple-choice");
var startButton = document.querySelector(".start-button");

console.log(quizQuestion);
console.log(multipleChoiceList);
//variable that holds the user's score
var score;

//variable that holds the time remaining for the quiz
var timeLeft;

//this array holds all the questions. each array element is an object with 3 parameters
var questions = [
    q1 = {
        question : "Which of these is a valid Markup language?",
        multipleChoice : ["python", "C++", "HTML", "Microsoft"],
        correctChoice : "HTML"
    },
    q2 = {
        question : "What does 'bit' mean?",
        multipleChoice : ["a little bit", "itty bitty", "Ribbit", "binary digit"],
        correctChoice : "binary digit"
    },
    q3 = {
        question : "What is the home page of a website usually called?",
        multipleChoice : ["index.html", "index[1]", "home.com", "None of the above"],
        correctChoice : "index.html"
    },
    q4 = {
        question : "Where in our HTML file to we link to stylesheets and libraries that the page will access?",
        multipleChoice : ["the JS File", "the <head> element", "the <html> element", "the <header> element"],
        correctChoice : "the <head> element"
    },
    q5 = {
        question : "How many <div> elements can you use in an HTML file?",
        multipleChoice : ["1 for each letter of the alphabet", "2^n, where n is the size fo your RAM in bytes", "as many as you need", "128"],
        correctChoice : "as many as you need"
    },
    q6 = {
        question : "Which of these isn't a valid command in Javascript?",
        multipleChoice : ["Math.floor(2.62);", "document.write('Hello World');", "var temperature = 98.6;", "for(each): run{foo};"],
        correctChoice : "for(each): run{foo};"
    },
    q7 = {
        question : "What doees CSS stand for?",
        multipleChoice : ["Central Styling Symbols", "Create Small Sponges", "Cascading Style Sheet", "Cest Son Sac"],
        correctChoice : "Cascading Style Sheet"
    },
    q8 = {
        question : "What is the unsyntaxed code you may use to plan your program called?",
        multipleChoice : ["psudocode", "precode", "library", "object-oriented programming"],
        correctChoice : "psudocode"
    },
    q9 = {
        question : "Which of these lines of JS code will set the variable 'input' to a value given by the user?",
        multipleChoice : ["var num = input;", "var prompt = input('Give me a number!');", "var input === 'Give me a number!'", "var input = prompt('Give me a number!);"],
        correctChoice : "var input = prompt('Give me a number!);"
    },
    q10 = {
        question : "How many times will the given loop run: for(var i = 0; i < 9; i++)",
        multipleChoice : ["10", "3^2", "i", "2^i"],
        correctChoice : "3^2"
    }
];

//This is the function that renders the question to the page
function renderQuiz(questionNum){

    //first clear the elements
    quizQuestion.textContent = "";
    multipleChoiceList.innerHTML = "";

    //creates an easily accesible object containing the current question
    var questionObject = questions[questionNum];

    //next display the question and create the answers in a list
    quizQuestion.textContent = questionObject.question;
    for(var i = 0; i < questionObject.multipleChoice.length; i ++){
        var multChoiceli = document.createElement("li");
        multChoiceli.setAttribute("id", "possible-answer")
        multChoiceli.setAttribute("class", "row m-1")
        multChoiceli.textContent = questionObject.multipleChoice[i];
        var selectButton = document.createElement("button");
        selectButton.setAttribute("class", "button rounded-button float-right m-1");
        selectButton.textContent = "SELECT";

        multChoiceli.appendChild(selectButton);
        multipleChoiceList.appendChild(multChoiceli);
        selectButton.addEventListener("click", function(event){
            //next questino function
        })
    }

}

function renderScores(){
    var containerEl = document.querySelector(".container");
    var btnEl = document.querySelector("#btn");
    var colClass = "col-md-4 text-center border bg-light";


}

startButton.addEventListener("click", function(){
    var questionsIndex = 0;
    renderQuiz(questionsIndex);
});


